Finding Aid for D.C. Allen House of David Collection, 1795-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual Materials
  - Photographic prints, 1906-1970circa 1906-1940 (Box 19)
    - People, 6 folders
      - Purnell family
        - Benjamin and Mary (includes "dialogue" scene) (Box 19)
        - Mary (Box 19)
        - Mary w/ others (Box 19)
        - Family portraits & children (Box 19)
    - Printed materials (photographs of)
      - Correspondence (Box 19)
      - Diagrams of bowling alley machinery, toilet seat and boat propeller designed by Benjamin (Box 19)
      - Drawings by Benjamin (Box 19)
      - Hymns (sheet music) with words by Benjamin (Box 19)
      - Items related to other prophets/leaders (Box 19)
    - Other
      - Advertisements, including Shiloh's Messenger Carriage (Box 19)
      - Australians' arrival (Box 19)
      - Baseball grounds and vehicles (Box 19)
      - Boats (Box 19)
      - Bus to Mary's House of David (Box 19)
      - Color postcards, oversized 1968 (Box 19)
        (regular-size postcards in box 20)
      - Dental department (Box 19)
      - High Island (Box 19)
      - Ice cutting (Box 19)
      - John Wroe Church (Victoria, Australia) (Box 19)
      - Mineral Springs (Box 19)
      - Parades (Box 19)
      - World's Fair Busses (Box 19)
  - Post Cards
    - Australians' arrival (Box 20)
    - Automobiles, miniature (Box 20)
    - Boat trip to promote H. O. D. (Box 20)
    - Buildings
      - Bethlehem & Jerusalem (Box 20)
      - Diamond House (Box 20)
      - Shiloh (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Businesses, miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - City of David (Box 20)
    - Eden Springs Park (Box 20)
    - Grande Vista Motor Court (Box 20)
    - Mary's Vegetarian Restaurant (Box 20)
    - Model House (Box 20)
    - Open Air Theater (Box 20)
    - Parade Cars & Floats (Box 20)
    - Park Fountain (Box 20)
    - People
      - Baseball team (Box 20)
      - Children (Box 20)
      - Entertainers (non-musical) (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Groups (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Portraits (Box 20)
      - Musical Groups
        - General (Box 20)
        - Women (Box 20)
      - Purnell family
        - Benjamin (Box 20)
        - Mary (Box 20)
        - Mary and Benjamin (Box 20)
    - Sunset Motel (McAllen, Texas) (Box 20)
    - Trains, miniature (Box 20)
    - World's Fair booth (Box 20)
    - House of David Park and Enterprises, 1 packets (Box 20)
  - Negatives
    - Film
      (Prints available in collection)
      - Numbered, 31 negatives b/w, 4"x5" (Box 21)
        (Numbered 24,596 through 24,626 according to system at previous repository; numbers match with prints integrated into topical arrangement above.)
      - Topical, 3 folders mostly b/w, 5"x7"
        - Administrative workers (Box 21)
        - Advertisements (Box 21)
        - Art shop and products (Box 21)
        - Australians' arrival 1905 (Box 21)
        - Automobiles, miniature (Box 21)
        - Baseball park (Box 21)
        - Boats (Box 21)
        - Buildings (Box 21)
        - Dental office, circa 1910 (Box 21)
        - Eden Springs / House of David Park (Box 21)
        - General, early 20th century (Box 21)
        - Color and b/w 1970 (Box 21)
        - Food products and cannery (Box 21)
        - High Island (Box 21)
        - Lewis, Joe with H. O. D. members 1936 (Box 21)
        - Machine Shop and printing shop (Box 21)
        - Musical groups (Box 21)
        - Musical instrument making (Box 21)
        - People, miscellaneous. (Box 21)
        - Souvenir shop and products (Box 21)
        - Trains, miniature (Box 21)
        - World's Fair busses (Box 21)
    - Glass negatives, circa 1918-1927, 39 negatives 5"x7"
      (prints available in the collection)
      - The Ark (Box 21)
      - Baseball Grounds (H. O. D. vs. Chicago Giants) (Box 21)
      - Boats (Box 21)
      - Children (Box 21)
      - Correspondence (Box 21)
      - High Island (Box 21)
      - House of David Park 1927 (Box 21)
      - Men at Mineral Springs (Box 21)
      - Parade (Box 21)
      - Patents (toilet seat, bowling alley mechanism) (Box 21)
      - Portraits (Box 21)
    - Film negatives
      (Prints not available in collection)
      - Mary's House of David free bus (Box 22)
      - Documents (photographs of)
        - Envelopes addressed to Reorganized House of David 1934 (Box 22)
        - Phone Bill 1926 (Box 22)
      - House of David Cold Storage Bowling Team 1946 (Box 22)
      - Legal documents related to Hansel v. Purnell 1929 (Box 22)
      - Parade float 1939 (Box 22)
      - Preaching trip by Askerlund and Pyke 1921-1922 (Box 22)
      - Rooms with peep holes in walls 1930 (Box 22)
      - Streamline trailer built by H. O. D. 1935 (Box 22)
      - World's Fair souvenir store 1933 (Box 22)
  - Slides
    - Film, 5 slides color, 1"x1"
      - Boone, Dannie and Eddie (Box 22)
      - Wm. Wright house (Box 22)
      - Group of people near agricultural fields (Box 22)
    - Glass, 95 slides 3.25"x4"; color, hand-tinted and b/w
      (images are mostly duplicative of ones available in Photograph and/or Postcard subseries; only exceptions to this, i.e. images not available elsewhere in the collection, are listed below)
      - Benjamin's drawings, including one of Mary, 11 slides (Box 22)
      - Benton Harbor Exchange Club entertaining orphans at park (Box 22)
      - Blossom parade floats and prizes (Box 22)
      - Boiler room with worker (Box 22)
      - Farms, including raspberry fields and orchards (Box 22)
      - Greenhouse interior images (Box 22)
      - High Island saw mill and view from the lookout (Box 22)
      - Kangaroos at the H. O. D. "Australian Headquarters" (Box 22)
      - Lumberyard (Box 22)
      - Portrait of Coy Purnell taken at outdoor photo gallery (Box 22)
      - Zoo animals, including peacock and Irish the monkey (Box 22)
      - Winter scenes of H. O. D. buildings (Box 22)
- Realia
  - Etched printing plates used in the production of postcards and other advertising materials (Box 23)
    (images not duplicated in the postcard files)
  - Promotional materials and other items bearing stamp of House of David; include advertising cards, selection of items from gift shop, pens and pencils, product labels (Box 23)
  - Advertising Cards
    - The Christian Israelite Church (Indianapolis, Indiana) (Box 23)
    - House of David Quartet ("Quartette") (Box 23)
    - Mary's Restaurant and Hotel (Box 23)
  - House of David Park season pass and miniature railway tickets (Box 23)
  - House of David membership card (Box 23)
  - Saint Joseph Souvenir Images (includes H. O. D.) (Box 23)
  - Calendars (Box 24)
  - Poster of Jesus the Good Shepherd by Benjamin (Box 24)